goreadgreen.com 2011-10-31

# Privacy Policy | The Read Green Initiative

## Privacy Policy

The Read Green Initiative knows that you care how information about you is used and shared, and we appreciate your trust that we will do so carefully and sensibly. This Policy explains The Read Green Initiative’s treatment of information that we collect when you are on The Read Green Initiative Web site and when you use our products and services (collectively, “The Read Green Initiative Service”), which may include personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”). By using The Read Green Initiative’s products and services, you are accepting the practices described here. 

This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that The Read Green Initiative does not own or control, or to individuals that The Read Green Initiative does not employ or manage, including operators of Web sites you may visit before or after visiting The Read Green Initiative Web site and the owners or publishers of the magazines and other products (“Publications”) you purchase, download or otherwise access through The Read Green Initiative Service. 

**Information We Collect**  
The Read Green Initiative collects information from users, which may include Personal Information, at different points on our Web site and through our software as follows:

**Information You Give Us**  
We receive and store information you enter on our Web site or give us in any other way.

  * _Registration data:_  
When you register for The Read Green Initiative Service, we ask that you provide basic contact information such as your name, address, and email address.
  * _Order data:_  
When you order Publications through The Read Green Initiative Service, we collect your purchase and address or billing information, including your credit card number and expiration date.
  * _Voluntary information:_  
We may collect additional information at other times, including but not limited to, when you provide feedback, change your content or email preferences, respond to a survey, or communicate with The Read Green Initiative Customer Support.
  * _Information Collected Automatically:_  
We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us via The Read Green Initiative.com or The Read Green Initiative Reader software.
  * _Computer configuration:_  
We automatically receive and log information from your browser, including your IP address, your computer’s name, your operating system, browser type and version, CPU speed, and connection speed.
  * _Referral, clickstream, and site interaction data:_  
We may also record the URL you linked from to get to The Read Green Initiative.com, your clickstream through and from our Web site, and other generally accepted tracking information.
  * _Email delivery and open rates:_  
To help us make our emails more useful and interesting, and to ensure that we are delivering the Publications you have ordered, we often receive a confirmation when you receive and/or open email from The Read Green Initiative.
  * _Software installation, file downloads, and publication access:_  
When you install The Read Green Initiative Reader or download Publications or other files from The Read Green Initiative.com, we may record when each file transfer begins and ends, and any errors that interrupt the transfer. The Read Green Initiative Reader software also records whether or not you downloaded and accessed a given Publication.
  * _Information from Other Sources:_  
We may receive information about you from other sources, add it to our account information and treat it in accordance with this policy.
  * _Customer and order data from our partners:_  
If you place an order for a Publication directly with the publisher or another The Read Green Initiative partner for which we provide fulfillment or other services, your account information and order information is passed to us.
  * _Updated delivery and address information:_  
We may obtain updated contact information from third parties in order to correct our records and fulfill your orders or deliver communications to you.
  * _Demographic and purchase information:_  
We may reference other sources of demographic and purchase information in order to provide you with more targeted communications and promotions.

**How We Use Cookies**  
Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that a Web site can store on your computer’s hard drive. When you visit The Read Green Initiative.com, create a user account, download or purchase a product from us, or sign-in to The Read Green Initiative Reader we may set cookies on your personal computer. We require that cookies be enabled in your Web browser so that we can identify you as a repeat visitor or customer and maintain session information for logged-in users. We also use cookies to track usage trends and patterns in order to better understand and improve areas of our Web site.

The Read Green Initiative may allow other companies that are providing content on our site to set and access their own cookies on your computer. Other companies’ use of cookies is subject to their respective privacy policies.

**How We Use the Information We Collect**  
The Read Green Initiative uses this information to:

  * Deliver the Publications and other products you order or that are sent to you as sample or pass-along issues
  * Verify access to secure content and your account information
  * Determine whether you meet the minimum system requirements for use of The Read Green Initiative Service
  * Provide you tailored content and instructions, renewal options and targeted promotions
  * Service your customer support requests
  * Ask you to participate in surveys about our products and services
  * Offer you product upgrades
  * Better understand, on an anonymous and aggregated basis, how The Read Green Initiative Service is being used, including Web traffic and reading patterns, so that we may continually improve our products and services

See below for a description of The Read Green Initiative’s practices regarding e-mail communications to our users and how to update your preferences with respect to such e-mail communications. 

**How We Share the Information We Collect**  
We may share your Personal Information only as follows:

  * _Publishers and partners:_  
The Read Green Initiative may provide publishers and other merchants for whom The Read Green Initiative sells or distributes Publications or other products, with any Persona Information in connection with or as is necessary to fulfill your requests for their products, programs or services, or to satisfy other core business functions. In such instances, your Personal Information is governed by their respective privacy policies.
  * _Agents:_  
We may employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf such as fulfilling orders, sending email, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. They will be provided access to Personal Information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes.
  * _Protection of The Read Green Initiative.com and others:_  
We release account and other Personal Information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law; to enforce or apply our Terms of Service, The Read Green Initiative Reader License Agreement, or other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of The Read Green Initiative.com, our users, or others.
  * _Business transfers:_  
The Read Green Initiative may transfer information it collects, including any Personal Information, in connection with a business combination transaction or sale of all or most of the assets of the company. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of The Read Green Initiative may continue to use your Personal Information as set forth in this policy.
  * _Trusted third parties:_  
With your consent, we will make your Personal Information (not including your credit card information) available to trusted third parties who offer products and services we think may be of interest to you so that you can receive information or opportunities related to those products and services. You may update your preference with regard to our sharing your information for this purposeby opting in in the Your Account area of The Read Green Initiative Web site. A trusted third party may use shared information in accordance with its own privacy policy.
  * _With your consent:  
_  
Other than as set out above, you will receive notice prior to our sharing your Personal Information with any third parties, and you will have an opportunity to choose not to share the information.

The Read Green Initiative reserves the right to use and disclose anonymous information, including aggregate information derived from your Personal Information, to inform publishers, partners, and other interested parties as to the usage habits or characteristics of The Read Green Initiative’s user base; and to serve other general business purposes.

**Email Communications to our Users**  
The Read Green Initiative does not send unsolicited email, but we do send email communications to our users in connection with our providing The Read Green Initiative Service. The following outlines the types of email The Read Green Initiative sends to our users, and the choices you have about which messages to receive.

  * _Messages required to service orders you place for Publications and products fulfilled by The Read Green Initiative:_  
The Read Green Initiative will send you email notifying you of the availability of each magazine issue or other product that you order either directly from The Read Green Initiative or from one of our publisher or other merchant partners. We may also send you communications related to your order, for example encouraging you to pay for, register for the auto-renewal option for or renew your subscription.
  * _Messages required to service your The Read Green Initiative account:_  
The Read Green Initiative may send newly registered users a welcoming email, as well as messages confirming each order you place directly at The Read Green Initiative.com; confirming your account changes; inviting you to participate in customer surveys; and informing you of important product or service updates related to our core business.
  * _Marketing messages about Publications you receive:_  
We may send you marketing messages related to the Publications you receive, for example, encouraging you to purchase additional single copies or to subscribe.
  * _Optional marketing messages from The Read Green Initiative:_  
Registered users may also occasionally receive information or special promotions from The Read Green Initiative about additional Publications, products and services. You may update your preference with regard to receiving such messages by opting out in the Your Account area of The Read Green Initiative Web site.
  * _Optional marketing messages from trusted third parties:_  
With your consent, The Read Green Initiative may share your Personal Information (not including your credit card information) with trusted third parties so that you may receive information or opportunities from them about relevant products and services they offer. You may update your preference by opting in in the Your Account area of The Read Green Initiative Web site.

**Changing or Removing Your Information**  
To review or update your Personal Information, or to alter your email preferences, or preferences regarding how we share your Personal Information, visit the Your Account area of The Read Green Initiative.com.

If at any time you would like to close your account, send email to [support@zinio.com](mailto:support@zinio.com). Your Personal Information will be removed from our active user database and will be deleted assuming that you are current with all payment obligations, that The Read Green Initiative does not believe it reasonably necessary to keep such information for any pending legal action, and that we are under no other legal obligation to retain such information. Please be aware that any unfulfilled subscriptions may be canceled without refund and you will have to re-register in order to use The Read Green Initiative Service. It is your responsibility to request a refund from The Read Green Initiative or the appropriate merchant.

**Security Practices**  
The Read Green Initiative uses reasonable and current security methods to protect your personal data. Your information will be stored in a database located behind multiple firewalls and accessible only to authorized personnel. We do not encrypt normal Web sessions, but any transmission to our servers of credit card or other Personal Information uses Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input. Password and credit card information is then stored in our database in an encrypted, non-human readable form. (Note: Unless you are PCI DSS compliant, you should not be receiving, storing or accessing credit card data. If this statement pertains to how your payment processor manages andsecures credit card data this should be reflected in this policy.)

**Children**  
The Read Green Initiative does not knowingly collect, either online or offline, Personal Information from persons under the age of thirteen.

**Notification of Changes**  
From time to time, The Read Green Initiative may revise this Privacy Policy to keep it up to date with The Read Green Initiative’s products and services. The update date is used to alert you to recent changes. If changes to The Read Green Initiative’s privacy policy will directly affect how we share your Personal Information, we will notify you by posting a notice on our Web site and by sending you an email giving you an opportunity to opt out of such change. Unless we notify you otherwise, our collection and use of your Personal Information is governed by the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such Personal Information is collected.

**How to Contact Us**  
If you have any questions or concerns regarding our Privacy Policy or our use of your information, please email [**support@zinio.com**](mailto:support@zinio.com) or use the following address:

The Read Green Initiative  
114 Sansome Street, 10th Floor  
San Francisco, CA 94104
